ravinia.org 2019-03-07

# Ravinia Festival Official Site | Privacy Policy

This Web site is the responsibility of Ravinia Festival Association (“Ravinia”). If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us through our Web site or contact us by mail at 418 Sheridan Road, Highland Park, IL 60035 or by e-mail at webmaster@ravinia.org. The Web server on which this Web site is housed is owned and maintained by Ravinia Festival Association. The following policies apply to www.ravinia.org.

## Commitment to Privacy

Your privacy is important to us. When you visit our Web site, you are accepting the terms and practices outlined in this Privacy Policy. Please take a moment to read our Privacy Policy prior to using the Web site.

### The Information We Collect and How We Use It

Ravinia may collect the following types of information through Ravinia.org:

  * **Identifying Information** – When you sign up for a MyRavinia account, we ask you for personal information, such as your name, email address and an account password. Ravinia uses this information to fulfill your requests for our programs and services, to respond to your inquiries about our offerings, and to offer you other programs or services that we believe may be of interest to you. During ticket purchases or other online transactions, we also request credit card or other payment account information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers.
  * **Contests, Sweepstakes and Special Offers** – From time to time, Ravinia will conduct various contests, sweepstakes, or other special offers. If you choose to participate in a contest, sweepstakes, or special offer through Ravinia.org, we may ask you to submit certain personal identifying information, such as your name, address, age and other information, in connection with that offering. This information may be used to contact you or to provide you or other users with a more personalized service going forward.
  * **Log information** – When you access any of the areas within Ravinia.org, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a Web site. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address (the IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are accessing the Internet), browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. This information does not include personally identifiable information. We may use this data to assist us in evaluating the usefulness of our Web site as well as improve our services to you and other users in the future.
  * **Cookies** – Our web servers may seek (as many Web sites do) to place a "cookie" (a small data file) on your computer's hard drive that allows the server to determine the computer when it visits again, in order to track statistical information about navigation to and throughout certain areas of our Web site. This cookie is not used to obtain your name or any personal data, and the information that is tracked is used only for internal purposes, such as to improve Web site navigation. If you prefer not to accept cookies, you can set your web browser to reject them or to alert you before one is placed, but some features and services on the Ravinia Web site may not function properly if you disable cookies.
  * **User communications** – When you send email or other communications to Ravinia, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to requests and improve our services.
  * **Links** – Ravinia may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our Web site and services.
  * Ravinia processes personal information on our servers in the United States of America only.

### Information We Disclose to Third Parties

Ravinia may use or disclose the information you provide about yourself to our contractors, agents and suppliers to fulfill your requests for our programs and services or in connection with the operation of this site. In addition, Ravinia may from time to time exchange names and mailing addresses with other not-for-profit organizations in the Chicagoland area for one-time use only. We may also disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. However, except as described above, Ravinia never trades, exchanges or sells email addresses or phone numbers with any other third party.

In addition, provided information is aggregated and does not identify you, you hereby acknowledge and consent to the use and distribution by Ravinia of any information obtained from you in a report that may be distributed to third parties in the ordinary course of Ravinia’s business and for research and statistical purposes.

### Opt-Out Page

You may opt out of having your personal information collected by Ravinia, used by Ravinia for secondary purposes, disclosed to third parties or used by Ravinia or third parties to send promotional correspondences to you, by contacting Ravinia at webmaster@ravinia.org.

### Information security

In an effort to protect your personal information we have implemented a number of safeguards. We operate secure data networks protected by industry-standard firewall and password protection systems. Access to information is restricted to authorized persons. Additionally, when your personal information is collected through our Web site, it is encrypted using industry-standard Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") technology. We periodically review our security policies and update them as necessary.

### Data integrity

Ravinia processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Ravinia takes reasonable steps to ensure that all personal information we process is accurate, complete and current. However, whether the information is accurate will ultimately depend on the information you submit and your prompt correction of your personal information whenever necessary.

### Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

Upon request via postal mail, e-mail, or phone, Ravinia will provide you with a summary your personal information retained by Ravinia. You may modify, correct, change, or update your personal record or cause your personal record to be removed from Ravinia's database. Ravinia will only send personal records to the e-mail address on file for the name associated with it.

### Collection of Personal Data from Children

In general, Ravinia.org is not intended for or marketed to persons under the age of 18. Certain areas of Ravinia’s Web site are marketed towards children. We take the privacy of your children very seriously and recognize the need to provide additional privacy protections for children under the age of 13 who visit our Web site.

Ravinia encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children.

Ravinia’s Right to Contact User Ravinia reserves the right to contact site visitors regarding this privacy policy, or any other policies or agreements relevant to site visitors.

### Ravinia’s Right to Change Privacy Policy

Ravinia reserves the right to change this policy at any time with or without notice. It is your responsibility to check back to this Web site to review revisions and changes to this privacy policy. Specifically, we encourage you to review this privacy policy each and every time you visit the Web site.

###### Last Modified on: February 19, 2010
